(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T02:07:23.869695",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
四六時中 帰りの会で
Every single time at the wrap-up meet,
面倒くささを押し付けられてる
the annoyances passed on to me,
何から何まで
from start to finish,
ねえ あたし の こと が 好き なら
Hey, if you love me,
気付いて 夢 を 見せて よ
notice me and show me a dream!
どうして わかっ て くれ ない の ?
Why won't you understand?
さあだんだんだんだん 黙れ黙れ黙れよ
Now, step by step, shut up, shut up, just shut up!
言えないね そんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words...
少しだけ 静かにしてほしいね
I want you to be just a little quieter.
私たち 待望へ
Towards our long-awaited...
世界ででででん伏せやーやーやー
In this world, boom boom boom, hide away!
果たすその日まで
Until the day we fulfill it,
ねねねねごくやーやーやー
sleep tight, yadda yadda yadda.
あなたの周りもよよよよけかーい！
Even around you, dodge it, dodge it!
接吻ででででん伏せやーやーやー
Kissing, boom boom boom, hide away!
今日も期待 そっちのけだね
Once again, you brush off my expectations,
家に帰るから 私ひとりでも やっておきまーすね
so even if I'm home alone, I'll take care of it.
すべて すべて すべて 任せて それをさせてよ 大事なことなの わかっているでしょ
Leave everything to me, you know it's important!
白く周回りの街で 面倒臭いまま
In this white, looping city, acting like it's a drag,
今日も遊ぶ過ぎていくのでしょう
today too, time will just drift away, won't it?
壁に水をあげましょう 時の流れ 忘れてた
Let's water the walls, I forgot the time.
さあだんだんだんだん 黙れ黙れ黙れよ
Now, step by step, shut up, shut up, just shut up!
言えないね そんな強い言葉は
I can't say such strong words...
少しだけ 静かにしてほしいね
I want you to be just a little quieter.
私たち 待望へ
Towards our long-awaited...
今と未来 見たかったはずなのに
Present and future, even though I wanted to see them...
世界ででででん伏せやーやーやー 見えるその日まで
Hide away until the day it appears!
どんどんどんどんええええん この世の理やーやーやー
On and on, bawling, the logic of this world!
酔い痴れででででん伏せさっさっさ
Drunk in ecstasy, boom boom, step right up!
あなたの街なら 片付けつくるわ バッテンさ
If it's your town, I'll clean it up with a big X!
世界ででででん伏せやーやーやー 果たすその日まで
Hide away until the day we fulfill it!
ねねねねごくやーやーやー あなたの周りもよよよよけかーい
Sleep tight, even around you, dodge it!
せせせせふくあれあれあいーや！ 約束の地まで
Wishing all the best until the promised land!
さあ掲げよバッテンバッテンででででん伏せやーやーやー 死んだらびーちぇすの愛をあけましょう
Now raise your hands, when you die, open the love!
ねえ あたし の こと が 好き なら
Hey, if you love me,
気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 夢 を 見せ て よ
notice me, notice me, and show me a dream!
どうして わかっ て くれ ない の ?
Why won't you understand?
嫌い だ 嫌い だ 嫌い だ 嫌い だ 二度 と 触れ ない で
I hate you! Don't touch me ever again!
ちょっと 待っ て どこ から おかしく なっ た の ?
Wait a second, where did things start going wrong?
ダメ な とこ も 好き に なれ て よかっ た のに
Even though I wished I could love even my bad parts.
ばっ と 飲ん で 誰 か に 埋め て もらえ たら あなた の こと 忘れ られる と 思っ て い た
I thought if I had someone else fill the void, I'd forget you.
トモダチ って 都合 よく ない けど 繋がっ てる なら 悪く は ない ね
"We're friends," what a convenient, yet not so bad connection.
騙し 騙し 生き て 病ん じゃ って 優しく さ れる と 余計 に ツライ けど 冷たく さ れる の 望ん で ない よ
Living in deceit, when you're kind it hurts, but don't be cold.
あたし だけ で いい よっ て 信じ ちまっ て バカ だ な
Believing "just me is fine" - how foolish.
ねえ あたし の こと が 好き なら
Hey, if you love me,
気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 気付いて 夢 を 見せ て よ
notice me, notice me, and show me a dream!
どうして わかっ て くれ ない の ?
Why won't you understand?
嫌い だ 嫌い だ 嫌い だ 嫌い だ 二度 と 触れ ない で
I hate you! Don't touch me ever again!
ダサい 感情 は 1…2…の…散 散 散 で 流れ 星 あ の 子 と の コト 呪っ て あげる わ ねえ
Uncool emotions scatter, I'll curse your affair with her!
愛し た 時間 を 返し て よ 嘘つき
Give back the time I loved you, you liar!
でも まだ 好き だ よ
But I still love you.
ギュッ って 吐い た そう ちゃん と 生き て 鼓膜 舐める 愛 の coda 溶かし 尽くす 煙る ソーダ
Living properly, the coda of love licking my eardrums, a soda.
ねぇ 置い て か ない で ねぇ お腹 空い た 見 て 見 ぬ ふり 唾 を 吐い て 燃え ない ごみ に する ん だ
Don't leave me. I'm hungry. Turning me into unburnable trash.
ねぇあたしのことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me,
気付いて
please notice me.
夢を見せてよ
Show me a dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの？
Why won't you understand?
嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 大嫌いだ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you so much!
あなたは振り向かないの
You won't even look back at me.
気づいてる 気づいてる 気づいてる 気づいてる
You know it, you know it...
癖にわたしはどうしてばっか変われないの
Even though you know, why can't I ever change?
したいよ したいよ したいよ したいよ
I want to, I want to...
離れたくないよ
I don't want to part ways.
ダサい感情は1…2の…散で流れ星、あの子とのコト呪ってあげるわ
I'll curse my uncool feelings scattered in falling stars with that girl.
ねぇ最後にぎゅっとさせてほしい ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう
Hey, hold me tight at the very end. Thank you...
これであなたも
Now you too...
往生しようぜ この浮世の何千里
Let's pass away, thousands of miles through this floating world,
あまざらして噛み砕い 甘ずっぱいばっかのアイロニー
weathered and chewed up, irony of only bittersweetness,
ピートンたりやしない どうせこの日は爽しない
never enough, this day won't be refreshing anyway.
ちゃんと絡み合った手と手と手と 現せその声で
Hands intertwined properly, reveal it with that voice.
ああ遊びあそばせて 手の鳴る方へ
Ah, let's play, to where the hands clap.
浅ましがましやかまし 泣き面に蜂
Vile, greedy, noisy, misery loves company.
逃げ場もなくて ほら、この夜は空騒ぎ
With nowhere to run, look, this night is much ado about nothing.
想像したって この浮世は三千里
Even if I imagine it, this floating world is three thousand miles.
空回りの毎日 疑って設定は忠実に
Everyday spinning our wheels, doubting while the setup remains faithful.
愛楽は響いて忙し 揃うに服は青嵐
Joy and pleasure echo busily, matching clothes in a blue storm.
あの人は恋がたき？
Is that person a rival in love?
混じり合えないふたり 殺さんざな浮世に乾杯を
Two people who can't mix, a toast to this bleak floating world.
もうさよなら 知らない街で また出会いましょう
Goodbye now, let's meet again in an unfamiliar town.
ああ遊びあそばせて 手の鳴る方へ
Ah, let's play, to where the hands clap.
見惚れて射止めて 恋ごころ
Captivated, striking, a heart in love.
花びらはらり またふたう 法螺、あの人も嘘つき？
Petals flutter down, two more. See, is that person a liar too?
ああ遊びあそばせて 手の鳴る方へ
Ah, let's play, to where the hands clap.
浅ましがましやかまし 飲み干せ悪魔
Vile, greedy, noisy, drink it up, devil.
果てるまで 何せこの夜は寂しがり
Until the end, after all, this night is lonely.
間抜けな醜態だ 金輪際のさようなら 求め合うほど目眩く罪深き
What a foolish spectacle, goodbye for good, the more we crave each other, the more blindingly sinful.
飲み干せ悪魔 果てるまで 何せこの夜は寂しがり
Drink it up, devil, until the end, after all, this night is lonely.
ああ遊びあそばせて 手の鳴る方へ この世は猿芝居
Ah, let's play, to where the hands clap, this world is a farce.
歪んで傷だらけの春 祭りも歌わずに歩いた
A distorted, scarred spring, I walked without even singing at the festival.
からだの奥底で響く 生きてないと強く
Echoing deep within my body, strongly feeling that I'm alive.
まだ味わうさ 神を恨み堪るの味 冴え切れないままの心で
I'll still taste it, the taste of resenting God, with a mind still unclear.
ひとつひとつ無くした果てに どうやく残ったもの
What finally remained after losing one by one.
これが愛じゃなければ なんと言おう
If this isn't love, what should I call it?
歪んだ傷だらけの春
A bruised and battered spring,
麻酔も打たずに歩いた
I walked on without even numbing the pain.
体の奥底で響く
Resonating deep within my body,
生き足りないと強く
a fierce hunger to live more
まだ味わい尽くす 噛み終えたガムの味
like the taste of chewed-up gum, still lingering on.
冷めきれないままの心で
With a heart that still cannot cool down,
ひとつひとつなくした果てに ようやく残ったもの
What finally remained after losing everything one by one...
これが愛じゃなければなんと呼ぶのか 僕は知らなかった
I didn't know what else to call this if not love.
呼べよ 花の名前をただひとつだけ
Call out the flower's name, just one name,
張り裂けるくらいに 呼吸が止まる
until my voice cracks and my breath stops.
痛みは消えないままでいい
It's fine if the pain never goes away;
疲れたその目で 何を言う
what are you trying to say with those tired eyes?
傷跡 隠して歩いた そのくせ影をばらまいた
I walked hiding my scars, yet scattered my shadow around.
気づいて欲しかった
I wanted someone to notice.
誰もしみじみと微笑むことが うまくできなかった
I could never smile deeply and genuinely like anyone else.
ひとつ、ただひとつでいい 守れるだけで それでよかったのに
Just one, just one thing to protect was all I wanted, even if that was enough.
あまりにくだらない願いが 消えない 誰にも奪えない魂
Such a foolish wish won't fade—a soul no one can ever steal.
何にたとえよう 君と僕を 踵に残る似た傷を
What can I compare you and me to? The similar scars remaining on our heels?
晴れ間を望めば まだ続く行こう 花も咲かないうちに
If we hope for a clearing, it still goes on. Let's go before the flowers even bloom.
これが愛じゃなければなんと呼ぶのか 僕は知らなかった
I didn't know what else to call this if not love.
呼べよ 恐れるままに 花の名前を 君じゃなきゃダメだと
Call out the flower's name in fear, insisting it has to be you.
張り裂けるくらいに 呼吸が止まる 痛みは消えないままでいい
Until my voice cracks and breath stops, it's fine if the pain never goes away.
あまりにくだらない願いが 消えない 止まない
Such a foolish wish won't fade, won't stop...
はい、ということで、4曲連続で聴いていただきました！
Alright, so you've listened to 4 songs in a row!
皆さん、まったかね～！ホロックスの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申します。
Everyone, Matatakane~! I'm Takane Lui, the female executive of HoloX.
二周年だー！イェイイェイイェイイェイ！ダンサーさんもありがとうございます！
It's our 2nd anniversary! Yay yay yay yay! Thank you to the dancers as well!
はい、ということで、ちょっと息を整えたいんだけど、いける？
Alright, so, I want to catch my breath a bit... can I do it?
ということで、えー鷹嶺ルイ2周年ライブ「ANIMAL」が始まりました！いぇーい！
So, um, Takane Lui's 2nd Anniversary Live "ANIMAL" has begun! Yay!
皆さん楽しんでおりますでしょうか！
Are you all enjoying yourselves?!
今回もね、あのハッシュタグございますので、あ、こっちかな？こっちかな？ここにありますのでよかったらたくさんポストしてください。
Also, we have a hashtag this time—is it this way? That way? It's right here, so please feel free to post lots!
ちゃんとポストって言いました！
I said "post" properly!
はい、ということでね、今回ね「ANIMAL」というタイトルをライブに使わせていただいたんですけれど、まあその意味も、まあ後々わかると思うのですが、
Yes, so, we used the title "ANIMAL" for this live performance, and well, the meaning behind it will become clear later on, but...
え、ANIMALね、ちょっと皆さんもうお気づきかかと思いますが、なんと曲名すべてね、動物の名前が入っている曲を集めさせてもって...
Um, about "ANIMAL", you guys probably already noticed, but all the song titles feature animal names gathered together...
まあパラサイトは寄生生物なんだけど、まあね
Well, parasites are parasitic organisms, but you know...
命あるものみんな動物だから、そういうところは気にしない気にしないね。
all living things are animals, so don't worry about things like that.
そうだよね、気にしない。そう気にしないということで、
That's right, don't worry. So, moving on without worrying,
演出とかもね、すごい今までちょっとこういうことやりたかったなっていうのをたくさん爆盛りさせていただいておるのですが、
we've packed in so many stage productions that I've always wanted to do up until now, but
このね、あとはしかも、えー、テンポラリーダンスをちょっとダンサーさんにしていただきまして、
and this time, moreover, uh, we had dancers do a temporary dance,
えー、ちょっと私が歌っている周りを回ってもらっていうね、演出をしていただきました。ありがとうございます。
and they circled around me while I was singing. Thank you so much!
すごいやりたかったんで、助かりました。
I really wanted to do that, so it really helped.
そして色々こだわりはこの後もあるんですが、
And there are various other details and preferences coming up after this, but
ちょっと大きなね、こだわりとしてこのステージ、皆さん見てください、
as a major detail, everyone, please look at this stage!
このステージ、本当にすごくないですか！
Isn't this stage truly amazing?!
いやあ、さあ、こういうあのステージでちょっと歌いたいです、っていうことで、
Yes, wanting to sing on a stage like this,
すごいなんか、あの難しそうな顔してたんだけど、いや、いけまーすってすごい自信を持ってね、ちょっと言ってくださって、
I was worried it looked difficult, but they confidently said "We can do it!",
で、本当にできるのかなって私ちょっと不安だったんですけど、これ仕上がってみて、もう大満足っていうか、私の想像を超えていった
and I was a bit worried if it was really possible, but seeing it finished, I'm beyond satisfied—it surpassed my imagination,
あのステージでこう歌えるっていうのは本当にね、本日幸せでございます。
being able to sing on that stage like this makes me truly happy today.
なでね、あのたくさん細かいところまで作っていただきましたので、そちらも注目していただければなと思います。
So, they made it down to the fine details, I hope you'll pay attention to those as well.
そして、次の曲もなんと、ちょっとした演出がありますので、ここのステージをちょっと演出の都合上ガラッと変えさせていただきます。
And for the next song as well, there's a little production, so we'll completely change this stage layout for it.
そして私が水を飲みたいのもありますので、ダンサーさんもね、ちょっとね、かけるということで、
Also, since I'd like to drink some water, the dancers will also step offstage for a moment,
ということで一緒にじゃあ、あのバイバイして、ちょっと一瞬待ってもらいましょうみんなに。ということで、え、みんな待っててね！
so let's wave goodbye together and wait just a moment, everyone. Everyone, wait for me!
はい、ということでお待たせ、みんな待ったかね。
Yes, sorry to keep you waiting, did you wait long, everyone?
ちょっとお水休憩も挟み、そしてじゃじゃーん、ピアノをね、用意していただきました。
We took a water break, and ta-da, they prepared a grand piano for us.
ということは、次はですね、そう、その通り、え、ピアノの伴奏でちょっと歌わせていただければなと思います。
That means, next is... yes, exactly, I'd like to sing with piano accompaniment.
そう、あの、弾き語りができたらいいんだけど弾き語りはできないので、ピアノを弾いてくださる方をちょっと紹介したいと思います。
I wish I could play the piano myself, but I can't, so I'd like to introduce the person who will play it.
ウイングさん！
Wing-san!
本日はよろしくお願いします。それではちょっと準備の方をよろしくお願いします。
Thank you very much for today. Let's get ready.
ということで、ピアノバージョンでお送りするわけなので、ちょっと緊張してるんだけれども、そう心を込めてね歌いたいと思います。
So, since we're delivering this in a piano version, I'm a bit nervous, but I want to sing it with all my heart.
この後にねウイングさんとメンバーシップライブも行いますので、よかったらメンバーシップに入って頂けると嬉しいです。
After this, Wing-san and I will also hold a membership live stream, so I hope you'll join the membership if you'd like.
楽しみにしててね。ということで、準備大丈夫ですか？ウイングさん。
Look forward to it! So, are you ready, Wing-san?
それでは聞いてください。ピアノバージョンです。で、お。
Then please listen. It's the piano version. Here we go.
ショーケースの中過ごしてた
I spent my time in a showcase.
誰もかれもが過ぎ去っていた
No one wanted me, and they all left.
怖かったんだあの日君に
I was so scared, up until you came
連れられるまでは
and brought me home.
僕と同じの小さな手
With your little hands just like mine,
転げ回りくすぐり合う僕ら
we were rolling around, tickling each other.
こんなに君のこと好きになってた
I’d fallen in love with you so much.
どんなときでも傍に居て
I’ll always be there for you
君が言うなら ああ
if you say so.
名前はレオ名前呼んでよ
My name is Leo. Call me by my name.
君がつけてくれた名前だから
Because that’s the name you gave me.
嬉しい時も悲しい時も
When I’m happy and when I’m sad,
傍に居ると決めた大事な人
I’m the precious person who decided to be by your side.
傍に居ると決めた大事人
...to someone dear to me.
君が大きくなるほどに
As you grow bigger,
僕との時間は減るが道理
it's only natural that time with me decreases.
遠くに君の友達同士 仕方がないよな
Far away with your friends, it can't be helped, huh?
最近つけるその香水 鼻の利く僕にとっては辛いや
That perfume you wear lately is painful for my sensitive nose.
今日も帰りは遅くなるんだろうか
Will I be coming home late again today, I wonder?
君が居ない部屋夢を見る
I dream of a room where you're not there...
あの日のことまた
reliving that day all over again.
名前はレオ 名前呼んでよ
My name is Leo, call me by my name!
君がつけてくれた名前だから
Because it's the name you gave me.
寂しいけれど 悲しいけれど
Even though I'm lonely, even though I'm sad,
傍に居ると決めた大事な人
you're the precious person I decided to stay beside.
君が誰かと暮らすことを 伝えに帰ってきた夜に
The night you came back to tell me you'd be living with someone else...
撫でてくれたね きっとお別れだね
you stroked me, surely this is goodbye, huh?
最後にさ会えたからねえ 幸せだよ
I'm so happy I got to see you one last time.
名前はレオ 名前呼んでよ
My name is Leo, call me by my name!
君がつけてくれた名前だから
Because it's the name you gave me.
もう泣かないでよ 名前呼んでよ
Don't cry anymore, call me by my name!
あの日より大きな手で撫でてくれた
Stroke me with a hand bigger than that day!
名前はレオ 名前呼んでよ
My name is Leo, call me by my name!
君がくれた名前で良かったよ
I'm so glad you gave me this name.
忘れないでよ それでいいんだよ
Don't forget it, it's okay like that.
新しい誰かにまた名前つけて
Give a name to someone new again...
突き止めたい 叶わない 君の正体は
Your true identity, which won't let you stop...
迷宮入りの 難解なミステリー
is a labyrinthine, hard-to-solve mystery.
心変わり 色変わり 軽やかに姿を変えたのは
Changing hearts, changing colors, lightly changing your form...
悲しいほどの夕暮れ 僕の知らない君は誰？
Who are you, someone I don't know?
急行列車が通り過ぎた
An express train has passed right by.
寂れた駅のホームには隙間風が吹き抜けた
A draft of wind blew through the deserted station platform.
君の姿はどこにも見当たらなくて
Your figure could nowhere be found,
時を経て通話画面に映った君は
and the you reflected on the video call screen over time
もう僕の知らない君でした
was someone I no longer knew.
幸せそうに笑うから つられて僕も笑ってしまった
Smiling happily, so I laughed along too.
何度でも 何度でも 塗り潰して
Painting over it again and again...
汚れた悲しみの 上から白い絵の具で 全てを台無しにして 放り出してしまった夜さえ
ruining everything with white paint over the stained sadness.
キャンバスは色付くから 涙滲んででにわか雨
Canvases take on color, so tears melt away into a sudden shower.
記憶の中の君と
Both you in my memory
今の君はどちらも真実で
and you right now are both the truth,
鮮やかに色めく君は もう僕の知らない色
Vividly vibrant, you are now a color I do not know.
何度でも 何度でも 塗りつぶして
Over and over, over and over, paint it over,
今の君にお似合いの 何色でも構わないの
whatever color suits you now, I don't care what it is.
伝えたいこの想い それすら叶わないけど
This feeling I want to convey—even if that won't come true,
口にすれば単純な強がり 隣に僕がいなくても
if spoken aloud, it's just simple bravado, even if I'm not by your side.
突き止めたい 叶わない 君の正体は
I want to find out, though I can't—what you really are
迷宮入りの難解なミステリー
is a labyrinthine, unfathomable mystery.
鮮やかに姿を変えたのは 哀しいほどの夕暮れ
Vividly changing your form, in a sadness-inducing twilight,
僕の知らない君は誰？
who are you that I do not know?
信号は青なのか それとも緑なのか どっちなんだ？
Are the traffic lights blue, or are they green? Which is it?
あやふやなものは はっきりさせたい
I want to make ambiguous things clear.
夕暮れ時の商店街の雑踏を通り抜けるのが面倒で
It's a hassle to walk through the bustling shopping street at dusk,
踏切を渡って遠回りして帰る
so I cross the railroad crossing and take a long way home.
放課後の教室は苦手だ その場にいるだけで分かり合ってるようで
I'm not good at after-school classrooms, as if we understand each other just by being there.
話し合いにならないし 白けてしまった僕は無口になる
We can't even have a discussion, and feeling left out, I become silent.
言いたいこと言い合って解決しようなんて楽観的すぎるよ
Saying our true thoughts and trying to resolve it is way too optimistic.
誰かがため息をついた そうそれが本当の声だろう
Someone let out a sigh—yes, that must be their true voice.
黒い羊 そうだ僕だけがいなくなればいいんだ
Black sheep, yes, it would be better if only I disappeared.
そうすれば止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろう
If I did that, would the stopped clock hands start moving again?
全員が納得するそんな答えなんかもるものか
Is there ever an answer that satisfies everyone?
反対が僕だけならいっそ無視すればいいんだ
If I'm the only one opposed, I should just ignore it.
みんなから説得されるほうが居心地悪くなる
It's more uncomfortable being persuaded by everyone.
目配せしている仲間には僕は厄介者でしかない
To the friends exchanging knowing glances, I am nothing more than a nuisance.
真っ白な群れに悪目立ちしている
Standing out awkwardly in a pure white flock,
自分だけが真っ黒な羊
only I am a pitch-black sheep.
と言ったって同じ色に染まりたくないんだ
Even so, I don't want to be dyed the same color.
薄暗い部屋のライトをつけるタイミングっていったいいつなんだろう
When is the right time to turn on the light in this dim room?
スマホには愛のない過去だけが残っている
My smartphone holds only loveless pasts.
人間関係の答え合わせなんて僕にはできないし
I can't figure out the answer key to human relationships.
そこにいなければよかったと後悔する
And I regret not being there.
人生の大部分は思うようにはいかない
Most of life doesn't go the way you want.
納得できないことばかりであきらめろとさとされてたけど
It's full of things I can't accept, and I was told to just give up.
それならやっぱ納得なんてもしないままその度に何度もつばを吐いてかみついちゃいませんか
So why don't I spit on those waves and bite back without ever accepting it?
全部僕のせいだ
It's all my fault.
黒い羊 そうだ僕だけがいなくなればいいんだ
Black sheep, yes, it would be better if only I disappeared.
そうすれば止まってた針はまた動き出すんだろう
If I did that, would the stopped clock hands start moving again?
全員が納得するそんな答えなんかもるものか
Is there ever an answer that satisfies everyone?
反対が僕だけならいっそ無視すればいいんだ
If I'm the only one opposed, I should just ignore it.
みんなから説得されるほうが居心地悪くなる
It's more uncomfortable being persuaded by everyone.
目配せしている仲間には僕は厄介者でしかない
To the friends exchanging knowing glances, I am nothing more than a nuisance.
分かっているよ 真っ白な羊なんて僕は絶対なりたくないんだ
I know that. I absolutely don't want to be a white sheep.
そうなった瞬間に僕は僕じゃなくなってしまうよ
The moment I become one, I would cease to be myself.
白い羊なんて僕は絶対になりたくないんだ
I absolutely don't want to become a white sheep,
そうなった瞬間に僕は僕じゃなくなってしまうよ
The moment I do, I'll stop being myself.
周りと違うそのことで
Just because I'm different from those around me,
誰かに迷惑かけたか
Did I cause trouble for anyone?
髪の毛を染めろという大人は何が気にいらない
What do adults who tell me to dye my hair find displeasing?
反逆の象徴になるとでも思っているのか
Do they think I'm becoming a symbol of rebellion?
自分の色とは違うそれだけで厄介者か
Just because my color is different, am I a nuisance?
自らの真実を捨て白い羊のふりをする者よ
Those who throw away their own truth and pretend to be white sheep,
黒い羊を見つけ
Will you find a black sheep
指を差して笑うのか
and point and laugh?
それなら僕はいつだって
If so, I will always,
それでも僕はいつだってここで悪目立ちしてよう
Even so, I will always keep standing out awkwardly right here.
ヘッドホン外して 一人きり歩く街
Taking off my headphones, I walk alone in the town by myself
迷っているのか 間違っているのか
Did I get lost? Did I take the wrong turn?
知らない場所みたいだ
Seems like a place that I don’t recognize
見えない信仰心 感じないシンパシー
My unseen devotion, sympathy that I don’t feel
俺にはないものばかりだ
And all the things that I can't have
なんのストーリー? 誰のストーリー?
What kind of story? Whose story is it?
手に入んなきゃ欲しくなるそうだろ
If you don't have something, you'll start to want it, isn’t that right?
合図くれよ マイクかざせ
Give me the signal, hold up the mic right now
あいつは今 追い風になびいていく
That guy's fluttering along with the tailwind
チャンスはきた ダイブすんじhater!
Here comes the chance! Time to dive, hater!
今リスタート決めて はじめて
Now, I’ve decided to restart for the first time
"みたい" ただそれだけでいいでしょ
Just saying "I want to be like you" is all you need, right?
理由なんて知らない 理由なんていらない
Not knowing the reason why, not needing the reason why
運命ルールに抗って
I'm defying against fate’s rules
今リスタート決めて 弾けて
Now, I’ve decided to restart and burst out
"見たい" ただそれだけでいいでしょ
Just saying "I want to see it" is all you need, right?
打ち鳴らせgroovy 聞かせなよheart beat
Let that groovy sound beat, let me hear that heartbeat
立ち止まる暇なんてないから
Since there’s no time to just stand still
アーアー マイクチェック ワンツー
Ah, ah, mic check! One, two!
all night でも 意外 余裕〜
It’s been all night but you’re unexpectedly composed ~
とか言うお前 マジで女優 (笑)
I’d say, you’re a real actress, ya know? (Lol)
上階階層? なら物申す!
You’re at the upper part of the society ladder? Then make a statement!
rad で bad な under dog がビビっときたね vividに染まれ
The rad and bad underdog surprised you huh, dyed you with vivid colors
上しかみてねえ今日のオマエは秘める闘志の 悩める勝ち犬
The you who haven't look up today is a troubled top dog that’s hiding its fighting spirit
合図くれよ マイクかざせ
Give us the signal, hold up the mic right now
俺らは今 追い風になびいていく
We're fluttering along with the tailwind
チャンスはきた ダイブすんじhater!
Here comes the chance! Time to dive, hater!
今リスタート決めて はじめて
Now, we’ve decided to restart for the first time
"みたい" ただそれだけでいいでしょ
Just saying "I want to be like you" is all you need, right?
理由なんて知らない 理由なんていらない
Not knowing the reason why, not needing the reason why
背徳の快楽 味わって
We enjoy the joys of immorality
今リスタート決めて 弾けて
Now, we’ve decided to restart and burst out
"見たい" ただそれだけでいいでしょ
Just saying "I want to see it" is all you need, right?
打ち鳴らせgroovy 聞かせなよheart beat
Let that groovy sound beat, let me hear that heartbeat
立ち止まる暇なんてないから
Since there’s no time to just stand still
追い風に吹かれて
With the tailwind blowing
Alright 振り向かず 進んで
Alright, we keep going forward without looking back
痛いことは嫌いですが
I hate things that hurt me,
君の手の平は嫌いじゃない
but I don't mind the palms of your hands.
言葉は飴玉みたいに 甘く広がってココロ満たす
Words like hard candy, spread sweetly and fill my heart.
呻吟全然分かってない
Groaning, you don't understand at all.
永遠に言う通り
Just as you always say,
完全にフェアじゃない
it's completely unfair.
（どこにいても）呻吟「何で？」は効いてない
(No matter where you are) "Why?" doesn't work.
もっともっとあの子みたいに 可愛くななくちゃ
I've got to be way cuter, more like that girl.
愛情は疎明に 傷痕はHow many?
Affection is clear, how many are the scars?
もう体痛いのだって分かんなくなる
My body hurts so much I don't even know anymore.
延命マタタビ 週二ご褒美
Life-extension catnip, twice-weekly reward.
「もう嫌だ」って離されないように
So you won't let go saying "I'm sick of this,"
今日だってちゃんとう内緒の毛づくろい
today too, I secretly groom myself properly
にゃんて良い子にするから
to be such a good kitty.
愛して Everybody today is a loving day!
Love me, everybody today is a loving day!
Get it get it, this is my courtship!
Any any any time is fine with me, gimme gimme love me, my darling!
Any time is fine with me, gimme love me, my darling!
会いたいを間違いなんて皆は言う 取り憑かれて言って
Everyone says wanting to see you is a mistake, possessed.
ならこの胸で穿く 締め付けるような切なさは何なの？
Then what is this piercing, tightening anguish in my chest?
選ぶ言葉 戸惑う指先 矯めな横顔
Choosing words, hesitating fingertips, a composed profile.
（私しか知らない）呻吟ランダムご機嫌 もしかして今日は優しく撫でてくれるのかな？
(Only I know) Random moods. Could it be you'll gently pet me?
君のそれが耐えられるの 生涯で私だけなんだよね
I'm the only one in a lifetime who can endure that of yours.
あからさまに カラダまさに 「もう嫌だ」って離されないよね そうだよね？
So obviously, you won't let go saying "I'm sick of this," right?
感情は上々 上々に訴えは少しに もう霊もさえるように転がせばいい
Emotions are at their peak, just roll over so spirits are clear.
柑橘の匂いだて凌ぐのだ もう片手しか殴られるだけだし
Outdoing citrus scents, getting beaten with just one hand,
今日だってちゃんとお膝でおとなしく にゃんてお好きなように 完全淘汰して
today too, nicely behaved on your lap, like a good kitty.
おめでとう！ おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
そうだ！ 一緒だよね ということでね
That's right! We're together, so...
ドロケンと、そして我々で2週連続で出ていただきまして、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for having us appear two weeks in a row!
いや、どうですか？ 実はね、うちら2周年にして、二人で歌うのは初めて。
Actually, for our 2nd anniversary, it's the first time we sing together.
いや、それ、テンション！
Hey, that tension!
そうなん、今日はとっても嬉しい日なのでテンション高いですけれど。
That's right, today is a happy day so our tension is high.
やっぱりさ、HoloXでデビューしてさ、最初うちらだったじゃんデビューしたのが、総水・幹部でさ。
We debuted first in HoloX, the head and executives.
結構みんなからの注目もあって。
There was quite a lot of attention from everyone.
で、色々2周年駆け抜け…駆け抜けてね。
And running through these two years...
駆け抜けてきたね。もうだって疲れてますから。
We ran through it. Because we're already tired.
駆け抜けてきたけど、どう？
We ran through it, but how was it?
はやいようで作ったな…
It felt fast...
色々…いや今日テンション何なんだよマジで！
No, what is this tension today seriously!
いや、楽しかったんですよ、今日はめっちゃくちゃ！
No, we had a lot of fun today!
そう、なんか今日は、2周年は、ツートップね、HoloXのツートップ、総水と幹部で歌って踊りたいなってことでお呼びさせていただきました。
Today for the 2nd anniversary, we invited the HoloX top two to sing and dance.
今日テンション高いな！ 嬉しくて体で表してるの、いや、めっっちゃおめでとう！
Our tension is so high today! Huge congratulations!
2周年さ、色々あったじゃん、お互いさ。
A lot happened during our 2nd anniversary.
ありました、とってもありました！ そう、なんか重要な時は会話したりとかしてたけど。
There were, very much so! We talked during important times.
まあ、いつもこう静かにお互い見守って、なんかやばそうだなと思ったら声かけてみたいなことを。
We'd quietly watch over each other, and if something looked bad, check in.
大丈夫？みたいなね！ そう、やってきましたね、ここまで。
Like "Are you okay?" Exactly, we've made it this far.
やっぱ応援してもらったし、いっぱい応援してね！
After all, we got supported, let's keep supporting!
からもよろしくお願いいたします。
...Looking forward to working with you too.
いいよ、おもろくないよ
Fine, it's not funny at all.
でね、明日はこよ、
And tomorrow, Koyori...
うん。
Yeah.
えー、黒江、いろはとね、ホロックスの周年続きますんで、
And Chloe, Iroha, and Holox's anniversary continues,
うんうん。まあ、やつらもね、発展こんなやつらなんだからね。
Yeah, yeah. Well, those guys are ever-evolving too,
みんな楽しみにしていただければと思います。よろしくねホロックスを。
so I hope you all look forward to it. Please support Holox!
と言うけどね、
Having said that though,
実はですね、この後とある発表とグッズ紹介を
actually, after this, we have a certain announcement and merchandise introduction...
とある方にしてもらおうと思っております。
...to be handled by a certain person!
え、違いますよ! 違います!
Eh? No way! That's wrong!
なんで? やりたそう、やりたそう!
Why? You look like you want to do it!
あ、じゃあ、あじゃあ、あの給付リーにして貰ってもいいですか? あ、給付リーいいよ! じゃあ、えー、VTRの給付リーをよろしくお願いいたします。
Ah, well then, please look forward to the VTR cue.
では、鷹嶺ルイのグッズ発表から10大発表の告知もぐ? とん! ぴ!
Now, for Takane Lui's merchandise announcements and the 10 major announcements—Mogu? Ton! Pi!
どうぞ! 一応やっててよ! 一応やっててよ! どうぞ!
Go ahead! At least keep posing! At least keep posing! Go ahead!
ということで、まずは私、鷹嶺ルイからのお知らせです。
And now, first is an announcement from me, Takane Lui.
私が大好きなアニメ『陰の実力者になりたくて!』第1期のオープニングテーマ、OxTさんの「HIGHEST」を歌ってみたが近日公開されます!
A cover of 'HIGHEST' by OxT, the opening theme of the first season of my favorite anime 'The Eminence in Shadow', will be released soon!
シャドウ様の格好をした鷹嶺ルイにも注目!
Pay attention to Takane Lui dressed as Shadow-sama too!
そしてそしてなんと、同じくアニメ『陰の実力者になりたくて!』第1期エンディングテーマ、ダリアンインザナイトの歌ってみたも近日公開予定です!
And what's more, a cover of 'Darling in the Night', the ending theme of the first season of 'The Eminence in Shadow', is also scheduled for release soon!
こちらは同じく陰の実力者が大好きなねね先輩とのコラボになっております! ソロもコラボも楽しみにしていてくださいね。
This is a collaboration with Nene-senpai, who also loves The Eminence in Shadow! Please look forward to both the solo and collaboration!
さあ、ここからはグッズ紹介の前に、何やらある方から発表があるらしいですよ! 一体誰からの発表なんでしょうか? それでは、どうぞ!
Now, before the merchandise introduction, it seems there's an announcement from someone! Whose announcement could it be? Well then, here it is!
陰の実力者。影に潜み、影を狩る者。
The Eminence in Shadow. One who lurks in the shadows and hunts shadows.
ということで、ルイさんからバトンタッチされたので、お知らせです。
So, since the baton was passed to me by Lui-san, I have an announcement.
YouTubeのチームキャラバンチャンネルで実施の「陰の実力者になりたくて! マスターオブガーデン」周年当日生放送に、鷹嶺ルイさんの出演が決定しました!
Takane Lui's appearance has been decided for the anniversary day live broadcast of 'The Eminence in Shadow: Master of Garden' on YouTube's Team Caravan channel!
何やらそこで10大発表もあるみたいなので要チェックです!
It seems there will be 10 major announcements there too, so definitely check it out!
いつも陰実、そして陰マスを応援してくれているルイさんの出演、楽しみにしています!
We're looking forward to Lui-san's appearance, who always supports Kagejitsu and Kagemasu!
さて、ここからは鷹嶺ルイ活動2周年記念グッズの紹介をさせていただきます。
Now, let me introduce Takane Lui's 2nd-anniversary merchandise.
まずは複製サイン入りアクリルスタンド。今回はMyungYi先生にイラストを描き下ろしていただきました!
First is the acrylic stand with a replica signature. This time, the illustration was newly drawn by MyungYi-sensei!
すくねモチーフのオリジナル部屋着がキュートででおしゃれ。複製サイン入りなので絶対ほしい!
The original room wear with a Sukune motif is cute and fashionable. It has a replica signature, so you definitely want it!
続いてはランダムアクリルキーホルダー。今回のライブテーマ、アニマルにちなんで動物と一緒のルイさんが4種類! イラストはYM先生の描き下ろし。
Next is the random acrylic keychain. Following the live's theme of animals, we have four versions of Lui-san with animals! Illustrated by YM-sensei.
お次はこちら、ルイのチョーカー風ブレスレット。ルイさんの特徴的なチョーカーがブレスレットに!腕につけてもよし、バッグにつけてもよし。
Next is this: Lui's choker-style bracelet. Lui's characteristic choker becomes a bracelet! Great on your arm or your bag.
使い方はあなた次第。推しと同じアイテムを身につけられるチャンス!
How you use it is up to you. A chance to wear the same item as your oshi!
続いて、つくね&つみれヘアバンド。つくねとつみれをモチーフにしたデザインが可愛い! もふもふふわふわな素材にこだわったとのことで、2個3個と買うのもあり。
Next, the Tsukune & Tumire hair band. The design featuring Tsukune and Tumire is so cute! Crafted with a fluffy, soft material, getting two or three is also an option.
最後にシチュエーションボイス。今回は「はじめての動物園デート」をテーマにルイさんが書き下ろしたシナリオに注目!
Finally, the situational voice. Pay attention to the scenario written by Lui-san with the theme 'Our First Zoo Date'!
もちろんフルセットもあります! フルセットの購入特典は直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードと特典ボイス「まったリ猫カフェデート」!
Of course, there's a full set! The full set bonus includes a signed cheki-style bromide card and 'Relaxing Cat Cafe Date' voice!
そして直筆サイン入りフルセット。今回はなんと無制限! サイン入りのチェキは初のグッズ化なのでお買い忘れのないように!
And the signed full set is unlimited this time! Signed chekis are a first-time good, so don't miss out!
以上、鷹嶺ルイ2周年記念グッズの紹介でした!
That was the introduction of Takane Lui's 2nd-anniversary merchandise!
ということで、ナレーションを担当したのは陰の実力者になりたくて! 影（シドウ）、そしてシャドウ役の声優、山下誠一郎でした! 改めてルイさん、活動2周年おめでとうございます!
And the narration was done by Seiichiro Yamashita, voice actor for Cid and Shadow in The Eminence in Shadow! Congratulations again on your 2nd anniversary, Lui-san!
えー、本当にホロックスさんはですね、私がホロライブを… おっ、ホロライブさんをね、おさせ頂いてから、えーデビュー配信を初めてリアタイできたユニット、グループということで、本当にこう特別なあの思い出というか、えー、あるんですけれども、そんな中でもルイさんはデビュー当初から色々な企画だったり様々なチャレンジをして、それを成功させていく、その成長している姿をもうあの、ファンの皆様にお見せしていらっしゃるっていうところで、本当に尊敬しております日々。
Um, truly, Holox... ever since I started supporting Hololive, they were the first unit whose debut stream I watched live in real time. They hold a truly special memory for me. Among them, Lui-san has taken on various plans and challenges since debut and succeeded at them. Seeing her continue to grow and show that to her fans everyday is truly respectable.
ウィーク、はい、など色々、
Week, yes, and various things,
なんだろ、色んなことに取り組んで挑戦して、
tackling various challenges,
ちょっと本もあったりとかなかったりとかしつつ、
with some books here and there,
あの日々頑張っている姿にこちらもなんか背筋が伸びるというか、あぁ、
seeing you work hard every day straightens my posture, like, ah,
これも自分の仕事頑張ろうって思わせていただいております。
it makes me think I should work hard on my own job too.
最近だと、えっとあれなんだっけ、リファインドセルフ、あの賢者すごくもう本当に
Recently, what was it called... Refined Self, that sage was really,
取れ高に愛された女幹部って感じで最高でした。
like a female commander beloved by high view counts, it was amazing.
はい。ということで、え、本当にいつも尊敬そして応援させていただいております。
Yes. So, I truly always respect and cheer you on.
これからの活動がどうかも素晴らしいものになりますよう応援しております。
I hope your future activities will be wonderful.
そして、ル友さん、ホロリスの皆さんも聞いていただいてありがとうございました。
And to Rutomo and all Holoris listeners, thank you for listening.
それでは、ここからはルイさんにお返しします。
Now, I'll hand it back over to Lui.
Atomic
I am Atomic.
はい、ということで重大発表もありの、ちょっと告知Vを見ていただきましたが、皆さんいかがだったでしょうか。
Yes, with the major announcement and the promotional video you just saw, how did everyone like it?
いやあ、ちょっと本当にびっくりすることばかりで、ええ、ちょっと私もドキドキしてるんですが、
Man, there are just so many surprising things, uh, my heart is pounding too,
やっぱりね、好きを伝えるっていうことは大事だなと、この2年間で、ええ、思いました。
but I've come to feel over these two years that conveying what you love is truly important.
好きを伝えれば叶うことだったりね、ええ、好きにこう関わらせていただくことが
If you convey your love, things can come true, and you get to be involved in what you love so much,
多いんだなという、本当に、ええ、ありがとうございます皆さん。応援ありがとうございます。
I've really felt how wonderful that is. Thank you everyone for your support.
そして、ええ、グッズ紹介はですね、ええ、私の大好きなその芸術のシャドウ様役をやっている山下さんに今回紹介していただきました。どうびっくりしたでしょう。
And for the merchandise introduction, Yamashita-san, who plays my beloved Shadow-sama in The Eminence in Shadow, introduced them for me this time. Were you surprised?
はい、グッズに関してはですね、1枚、今回1万円以下で買えるフルセットが買えるようになっておりまして、
Yes, regarding the merchandise, you can get the full set for under 10,000 yen this time,
ええ、直筆サインが無制限になっておりますので、1枚1枚ね、気持ちを込めて書かせていただきますので、
and since the handwritten autographs are unlimited, I'll put my heart into writing every single one,
ぜひぜひ皆さん、あの、お手に迎えてくれたら嬉しいなって思います。2周年の記念に、よろしくお願いいします。
so I'd be so happy if you could pick them up. Thank you for your support on our 2nd anniversary!
そして、ええ、ここまでやってきた2周年ライブなんですけれども、残り3曲になっております。3曲ね、ちょっと続けて歌わせていただくんですけど、
And for this 2nd anniversary live that has come this far, there are 3 songs left. I'll be singing 3 songs continuously,
この3曲はとある、ええ、クリエイターさんの曲を、まあ連続して歌わさていただくんですが、最後の曲がオリジナル曲になっております。
and these 3 songs are consecutively by a certain creator, but the final song is an original song.
え、オリジナル曲ね、もう2周年ここまでやってこれたのはみんなのおかげなので、ちょっと私をテーマに作った曲でございます。え、女幹部という肩書きでちょっと強めな感じに見えますが、
The original song... since we made it this far to the 2nd anniversary thanks to everyone, I made it with myself as the theme. With the title of "female commander," it might look a bit strong,
え、2周年やってみて、まぽんこつだったり、え、高値って苗字がついているのに高値の花っぽくなかったりとか、するっとう、まあうすうすというか、もう気づいていると思いますが、そういった、え、私をテーマにした楽曲になってますので、楽しみにしていってください。
but after two years, being a bit clumsy, or despite having the surname "Takane" (high peak) not acting like an unattainable flower... well, you guys probably already suspect or notice that, so it's a song themed around me, please look forward to it!
はい、で、続いでの曲は、え、ダンサーさんとちょっとおとなわせて、歌わせていただければなと思いますので、ちょっと呼び込みたいと思います。
Yes, and for the next song, I'd like to sing it together with dancers, so I'd like to invite them out.
まささん、やっこさん！はい、今日は来てくださってありがとうございます。
Masa-san, Yakko-san! Yes, thank you so much for coming today.
え、続いての曲はね、バニーという曲なんですけれども、バニーという曲が、まささんとやっこさんが、え、オリジナルで踊っているちょっと動画を拝見させていただいて、
The next song is called "Bunny," and I saw the original dance video by Masa-san and Yakko-san,
ぜひ一緒にパフォーマンスしたいなということで今回お呼びさせていただきました。ちょっと緊張するんですけど、近くでパフォーマンス見れるのもめちゃくちゃ嬉しい。ということで3曲連続で聴いてください。バニー！
and I invited them this time because I really wanted to perform it together. I'm a bit nervous, but I'm so happy to be able to see their performance up close. With that, please listen to 3 songs in a row. Bunny!
バニバニガール
Bunny, bunny girl,
ああ 求愛モード
Ah, requesting love mode,
擬態して恋してメロメロ
mimicking, loving, head over heels.
どうにもこうにもならない分かるけど
I know it's hopeless and nothing can be done,
あなたとせえ私だけ
but only you and I,
日も差っちもどうにも詰まるけど
both days and inches are hopelessly stuck,
二頭追うものなんせんまぬけのジク
chasing two hares, a clumsy zero-sense path.
くねるくねるばかりの辛い生活です
It's a bitter life of just twisting and turning,
ビジネスにんじあざとさ倍
business ninja, cunning multiplied.
きっちりばっちりあなたの前だけは
Neatly, perfectly, only in front of you,
すけまにハイキリップサービス
sheer-skin high-key lip service.
バニー バニバニ つけた耳
Bunny, bunny, bunny, attached ears,
怠れているバニー
slacking off bunny.
うさっちゃえと
Hop away and—
鳥カゴにフリーキーショー
A quirky show inside a birdcage,
鍵開けて?「私のセカイ」
Will you open the lock? "My world"
転んだり勘たり可愛いじゃ
Stumbling, guessing, how cute,
あざとさに掛けてる
Playing it so sly.
バニバニガール ああ やばいぞと
Bunny bunny girl, oh this is bad,
ハマっちゃいけないよね
I mustn't get hooked.
バニバニガール ああ 可愛いモード
Bunny bunny girl, oh in cute mode,
期待して恋してメロメロ
Expecting, loving, completely smitten.
うっかりぽっちゃり慣れないのウエイトは秘密
Carelessly, plump, my unaccustomed weight is a secret,
やっぱり当然乙女だもん
Naturally, I'm a maiden after all.
きっちりばっちり逆さげるルージュの花を
Neatly, perfectly hanging upside down rouge flowers,
お口に塗って軽めのウィング
Painted on my lips with light wings.
バニバニガール ああ
Bunny bunny girl, oh,
セノバラスな 下ろせないバニー
Bustling, an unyielding bunny.
嘘っちゃえ糞っちゃえまた罠に
Lie about it, shit about it, caught in another trap,
猛獣が傍に 逃げるわね
Wild beasts nearby, time to run away.
怒ったり泣いたり可愛いじゃ
Getting angry, crying, how cute,
リテラシー掛けてる
Showing your literacy.
バニバニガール ああ 若いことと
Bunny bunny girl, oh being young,
飛んじゃいけないよね
You shouldn't fly away.
バニバニガール ああ 主体モード
Bunny bunny girl, oh independent mode,
期待してそうしてボロボロ
Expecting, doing so, battered and worn.
くだらない半端で
With a silly half-hearted attitude,
ぽぼっちゃえ もっちゃえにぎりしょうばい
Pobocchae, mocchae, grip business,
うさっちゃえ とんちゃえたったじゃみん あいとるだろうバニー
Usachchae, tonchae, tatta jamin, aren't you open, bunny?
ころんだりかんたりかわいいじゃ
Stumbling, guessing, how cute,
あざとさにたけてる
Playing it so sly.
バニバニガール ああ やばいぞと
Bunny bunny girl, oh this is bad,
ハマっちゃいけないよね
I mustn't get hooked.
バニバニガール ああ 可愛いモード
Bunny bunny girl, oh in cute mode,
期待して恋してメロメロ
Expecting, loving, completely smitten.
可愛いけど愛して バニバニ
Even if I'm cute, love me, bunny bunny.
ああ 人生ゲームねフクロウさん
Ah, it's the game of life, Mr. Owl.
まだ面倒なんてやだった
I didn't want things to still be a hassle.
ラスト2曲、盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped for the final two songs!
全然足りないテスト赤点
Falling way short on tests, failing grades,
仕方がないから石を投げ
Since I have no choice, I throw stones.
万年冴えないお互いに万歳
Hooray for both of us being chronically dull.
努力がないから恨まれる
Resented because I lack effort.
ホロリホロリと泣き声が
Tearful, tearful crying voices
ポロリポロリ溢れ出した
Overflowing drop by drop.
ノラりクラリと生きたいな
I want to live idly and evasively.
ソロリソロリじゃいけないの
Can't I take things slow and steady?
やりがいなんてないなまけてたい
There's no sense of fulfillment, I just want to be lazy.
決め顔になれない嗚呼人生
I can't put on a cool face, ah, life.
おーまいがー 社会では
Oh my god, in society,
ヤンキーのこじゃいけないよ
You mustn't act like a delinquent.
おーまいがー 世間では
Oh my god, in the world's eyes,
フクロウが美徳になるから
Owls are considered a virtue.
天才少年は孤独を抱いて
The genius boy embraces solitude,
愛なんてないから眠れない
And cannot sleep because there is no love.
天然少女は良心も照れ
The natural girl feels shy about her conscience,
わざとじゃないから睨まれる
And gets glared at since it wasn't on purpose.
ホロリホロリと泣き声が
Tearful, tearful crying voices
ポロリポロリ明日濡らした
Soaked tomorrow drop by drop.
ノラりクラリと生きたいな
I want to live idly and evasively.
ソロリソロリじゃうるさいの
Taking it too slow is annoying.
問題だらけのフクロウさん
Mr. Owl is full of problems,
でも最強じゃんほら最強じゃん
But you're the strongest, see, the strongest!
将来なるならフクロウさん
If I become anything in the future, Mr. Owl,
ただ根性なんかね
It's just about guts, huh?
おーまいがー 奴らには
Oh my god, to those guys,
見えないものが多すぎて
There are too many things they can't see.
おーまいがー 世間では
Oh my god, in society's eyes,
真面目が美学になるから
Earnestness becomes an aesthetic.
何も背負わないで
Don't carry anything on your back,
無責任と流さないで
Don't brush it off as mere irresponsibility.
あなたが今飛び立つなら フクロウでもいいじゃないの
If you're taking flight now, why not be an owl?
人生ゲームねフクロウさん
It's the game of life, Mr. Owl.
もう関係ないほら関係ない
It doesn't matter anymore, see, it doesn't matter.
何年たってもフクロウさん
No matter how many years pass, Mr. Owl.
ホロホークなんてさ、
HoloHawk, you say?
オーマイガー！
Oh my god!
世間では 呑気になんかじゃいられないの
The world won't let you be carefree,
オーマイガー！ 世間では
oh my god! In this world,
苦悩が特別になるからさ
suffering becomes something special,
少しは中指立てちゃえば パッパッパ
so raising your middle finger a bit... pah pah pah!
単純で明白で 勘違いじゃない
Simple, obvious, and not a misunderstanding,
まだ妄想と妄想と 偏見でファイン！
still fine with delusions and prejudices!
そりゃ完全な万全な 設定じゃない
That's not a completely foolproof setting,
からかってくれないか
won't you tease me?
外見と内面と 偶像の不一致
Discrepancy between exterior, interior, and idol image,
この繊細さ 敏感さ 気安く触れ
touch this sensitivity and delicacy casually,
ほら冷徹な表情は ジンサイショウハイ
look, a cold expression is a deep defeat.
見つけてくれないか
Won't you find me?
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it away.
はいはい期待感 性癖おっしゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectation, state your fetish.
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it away.
はいはい期待感 性癖おっしゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectation, state your fetish.
ホロホロホッホロホッだけど 高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
Holo-holo-hop, but don't treat me like a flower on a high peak.
あのね 誰をも彼をも ワシと勘違い 驚きの愛
You know, mistaking anyone and everyone for me, surprising love.
ホロホロホッホロホッだけど ポンコツ味がちょいあるだけで新鮮 感動
Holo-holo-hop, but just a little bit of clumsiness makes it fresh and moving.
その際その際その際 受け止めてよね 高嶺の未来 乾杯
At that time, accept it, a high peak future, cheers!
ノルーダ ピエロ ダニ カリウオッチ
Noruda, pierrot, dani, kari watch,
しっかりウォッチ 曖昧 You know?
watch closely, vague, you know?
狩りとか苦手 モーキン類ね
Hunting isn't my thing, birds of prey,
一見クールね 意外とギャップ系
seemingly cool, surprisingly gap moe.
イメージ大変身 ノーグルOK？
Major image transformation, no gle OK?
大衆の歓声って 内気じゃない？
Isn't the roar of the masses timid?
ありゃ心配ね 散々で散々でも
Oh, it's worrisome, no matter how disastrous,
ただ正論や暴論の配信じゃない
it's not just a broadcast of orthodox or wild theories.
個人的見解 対 世界
Personal opinion versus the world.
ホロホロホッホロホッだけど 捕食しちゃうぞ だから怖がっちゃ嫌
Holo-holo-hop, but I'll devour you, so don't be scared.
ほらね爪も牙も おしゃれに研いで 隠しちゃいない
Claws and teeth, sharpened stylishly, not hidden at all.
ホロホロホッホロホッだけど 観察眼がちょいあるだけで緊張感
Holo-holo-hop, but just a bit of observational eye brings tension.
その際その際その際 受け止めてよね 高まる時代 乾杯
At that time, accept it, a rising era, cheers!
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it away.
はいはい期待感 性癖おっしゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectation, state your fetish.
はいはいお姉さん しまっちゃって行こう
Yes, yes, big sister, let's pack it away.
はいはい期待感 性癖おっしゃって行こう
Yes, yes, expectation, state your fetish.
ホロホロホッホロホッだけど 高嶺の花みたいに扱っちゃ嫌
Holo-holo-hop, but don't treat me like a flower on a high peak.
あのね 誰をも彼をも ワシと勘違い 驚きの愛
You know, mistaking anyone and everyone for me, surprising love.
ホロホロホッホロホッだけど ポンコツ味がちょいあるだけで新鮮感
Holo-holo-hop, but just a little bit of clumsiness makes it fresh.
その際その際その際 受け止めてよね 高嶺の未来
At that time, accept it, a high peak future,
乾杯 おいしょう 高まる時代 乾杯
cheers! Heave-ho! A rising era, cheers!
この後24時から先ほど披露した鷹嶺ルイ5曲目のオリジナル曲「ホロホーク」が各種音楽サイトで配信開始されます！
Starting at midnight tonight, Takane Lui's 5th original song "HoloHawk" will be available on various music streaming sites!
私のカバー曲でも人気の高いフクロウさんとエゴロックを制作したスリーさんによる完全書き下ろし楽曲になっております。
It's a completely newly written song by surii, who also produced "Owl" and "Ego Rock", popular cover songs of mine.
ちょっと真面目で堅そうに見えるけど、実はポンコツだし親しみやすいんだよという鷹嶺ルイを表現した1曲になっております。
It's a song expressing Takane Lui: someone who looks serious and stiff, but is actually clumsy and approachable.
スリーさんのアニマルシリーズらしさも出ていて、一度聴いたら忘れられないキャッチーな曲になっているので、たくさん聴いてほしいです。
It has surii's animal series vibe and is a catchy song you won't forget once you hear it, so please listen to it a lot.
そして24時からの配信に先駆けまして、このあと22時25分からホロホークのMVをプレミア公開いたします！
And ahead of the midnight release, starting at 22:25 tonight, we will premiere the "HoloHawk" MV!
こだわって作りましたので絶対見てくださいね！
We made it with great attention to detail, so please be sure to watch it!
メンバーシップ限定ライブもあります。
There is also a membership-exclusive live.
まだまだアニマルは終わらない！
ANIMAL is far from over!
メンバーシップライブも盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's get hyped for the membership live too!
2周年LIVE見てくれて本当にありがとう！この2年間楽しかったケド、つらくてくじけそうだった時もありました。
Thank you so much for watching the 2nd Anniversary LIVE! These two years were fun, but there were times when it was tough and I almost gave up.
でもこうやって無事に2周年むかえられたのは、みんなの支えがあったからです！！本当に感謝してもしきれない…
But the reason I was able to safely reach my 2nd anniversary like this is thanks to everyone's support!! I truly can't thank you enough...
これからも一緒に色々な夢を叶えていこうね☆どんな困難ものりこえる気がする！！よろしくね♪
Let's keep making various dreams come true together too☆ I feel like we can overcome any hardship!! Look forward to working with you♪